A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1906-1981; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 6.2 Linear feet Box 2-8, OV 28-29
  - General, 1906-1975; 2.1; Archival Resource Key
    - French and Company, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Frick, Helen C., 1947-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Funke, Mary-Louise, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - G Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Gainsborough's House Society, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Gallery of Modern Art (Ames, Winslow), 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Gillick, Mary, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Gluck, Helen, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Gluck, Helen, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Gluck, Helen, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Goldsmith's Hall, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Green, John, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Greene, B.M., 1958-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - H Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Handford, Hubert E., 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Harris, Paul S., 1967-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Harvard University, 1940-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hayes, John, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Hemp, W.J., 1958-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Houghton, G.F., 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Howard Young Galleries, Inc., 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Hutton, Edward, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - I Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Ivins, William, 1944-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Ivins, William, 1951-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Ivins, Barbara, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - J Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - J.B. Speed Art Museum, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - K Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Keck, Caroline, 1961-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Korchnoy, E.A., 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Korf, K. Frank, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - L Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Leggatt Brothers, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Leverhulme Research Fellowships, 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Lewis, Lesley, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Links, J.G., 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Little and Ives Co., 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - M Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Malden Public Library, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Marconi, Bohdan, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Martin, Mrs. Vincent, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - McCormick, Thomas J., 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Mitchell, John, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Montreal Museum of Fine Arts, 1959-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Muensterberg, Helene, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Mugar, Stephen P., 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Muller, Robert, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1959-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - N Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - National Buildings Record, London (Godfrey, Walter), 1941-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - National Gallery, London, 1929-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa, 1958-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nichol, E.G., 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - O Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Oxford University Press, 1954-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - P Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Pantzer, Kurt F., 1958-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Parsons, E., 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Phillips, Duncan, 1940-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Pignatti, Terisio, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Pilkington, Vere, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Poole, E.E., 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Pulitzer, Henry F., 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Q-R Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - R. Sovrintendenza Alle Gallerie, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Randall, Alec, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Rawlins, Ian, 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Rizzi, Aldo, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Rosenberg, James, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Rowley, Joshua, 1964-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Sa-Sh Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Si-Sz Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Sabin, Herbert H., 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Sachs, Paul, 1939-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Sanborn, Ashton, 1945-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Scrutton, Hugh, 1957-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Sewter, A.C., 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Slade Professorship, University of Cambridge, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Slade Professorship, University of Cambridge, 1935-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Smart, Alastair, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Smith College, 1947-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Society of Antiquaries, 1942-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Society of Dilettanti, 1936-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Society of Painters in Tempura, 1959-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - St. John's College, University of Cambridge, 1906-1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Stockwell, David, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Sulgrave Manor Board, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - T Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Tavern Club of Boston, 1942-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Thomas Nelson and Sons, 1960-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - U Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - U.S. Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - U.S. Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - U.S. Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - University College London, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - University of Auckland, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - University of New Brunswick, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - University Press Cambridge, 1937-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - V Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Vasalle, Rudolph A., 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vasalle, Rudolph A., 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Vassar College (McCormick, Thomas), 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - W Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Wallace Collection, 1924-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Windsor Art Association, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Winterthur Museum (Richardson, E.P. and Harris, Paul S.), 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Witt, John, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Y-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Unknown and Illegible, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Oversized material housed in OV 29.
    - Oversize Cartoon, Unknown and Illegible scanned with Box 5, Folder 17, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 29)
  - Committees, 1924-1976; 2.2; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence includes letters, memoranda, and reports related to ongoing committee objectives, projects, and routine activities. This sub-series also includes correspondence, updates, and recommendations related to Constable's advisory work with the Art Gallery of Toronto, Beaverbrook Art Gallery, National Gallery of Canada, and the Watts Gallery.
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - American Committee for the Restoration of Italian Monuments, Inc., circa 1946-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - American Committee for the Restoration of Italian Monuments, Inc., 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - American Committee for the Restoration of Italian Monuments, Inc., 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - American Committee for the Restoration of Italian Monuments, Inc., 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - American Federation of the Arts, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Beaverbrook Art Gallery, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Beaverbrook Art Gallery, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 2.
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - British Council, 1957-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1960-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - College Art Association of America, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1942-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Comite International D'Histoire de L'Art, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Committee for International Cultural Exchange, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Committee of the Iconographical Commission of the International Committee of Historical Sciences, 1934-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Committee of the Iconographical Commission of the International Committee of Historical Sciences, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Committee to Rescue Italian Art, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Committee to Rescue Italian Art, 1967 January-March; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Committee to Rescue Italian Art, 1967 April-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Committee to Rescue Italian Art, circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion (Nef, John U.), circa 1940-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion (Nef, John U.), 1946-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion (Nef, John U.), 1956-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Design and Industries Association, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Exploratory Conference on Conservation, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Exploratory Conference on Conservation, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Fine Arts Committee People-to-People Program, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Fine Arts Committee People-to-People Program, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1947-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - International Council of Museums, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1955-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1958 January-June; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1958 July-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects, 1965-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 1924, 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Lady Lever Art Gallery, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Lady Lever Art Gallery, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1937-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - National Cathedral Association, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1933, 1955-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1958 January-February; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1958 March-June; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1958 July-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (General), 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1933-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1955-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1959 January-June; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1959 July-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa (Museum Training Course), 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - New Brunswick Museum, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Renaissance Society of America, circa 1940-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1946-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Renaissance Society of America, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Walker Art Center, 1944-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Watts Gallery, 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Watts Gallery, 1960-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Oversize Blueprints, Beaverbrook Art Gallery scanned with Box 5, Folder 37, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 29)
    - Oversize Financial Chart, Art Gallery of Toronto scanned with Box 5, Folder 39, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa scanned with Box 7, Folder 23, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Condolences, 1976-1979; 2.3; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence consists of letters and cards from friends and family sent to Constable's wife, Olivia, after Constable's death in 1976.
    - List of Correspondents, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - A Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - B Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - C Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Constable, Olivia, 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - D-E Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - F-G Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - H Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - I-L Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - M-N Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - O-P Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Q-R Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - S Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - T-Z Miscellaneous, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - J.G. Links, 1964-1981; 2.4; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is between J.G. Links and Constable regarding the first edition of Constable's Canaletto, as well as proposed edits and changes to the second edition of the book.
    - Canaletto Research, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Canaletto Research, 1970-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Canaletto Research, 1976-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Lectures, 1909-1963; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 4.6 Linear feet Box 8-12
  Found here are over 170 drafts of Constable's lectures, and supporting notes and outlines. Topics range from surveys of 13th-20th century European and American art to museum conservation, ethics, art education, art collecting, and connoisseurship. There are numerous lectures on English and Italian painting, in addition to lectures on German, French, and American painting traditions. A handful of lectures on individual artists such as John Constable, Joseph Turner, Richard Wilson, Rubens, and Valasquez can also be found. The series also includes Constable's lecture notes from organized touring trips to Canada, Northern Europe, Scandanavia, and Poland.
  Lectures are arranged in alpha order by title. Materials retain their original order within each folder.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Lecture Announcements, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Lecture Slide Lists, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)